## Edem Alloh

669 High Clere, High Road, Buckhurst Hill, IG9 5HW | 07788 240 711 | info@edemalloh.com | http://edemalloh.com

## **Personal Summary**

A hard-working, motivated & determined web developer, specializing in front end technologies. With experience working in teams and solo, to achieve goals & deliver functionality within set deadlines. Able to deliver effectively & efficiently under pressure.

## **Experience**

#### FRONT END DEVELOPER | CUESONGS | FEBRUARY 2015 - MAY 2016

- > Design & maintenance of the core platform (an e-commerce website), using:
  - o HTML 5 & CSS3 (+ SCSS)
  - o jQuery (+ vanilla JS)
  - o Handlebars
  - Gulp for building distributables (bundling / optimization)
- > Creation of responsive HTML email templates for use with the core platform
- > Partial usage of PHP (Blade) for bug fixing and feature development
- > Management of the blog platform, which included
  - Designing layouts and implementing articles written by the editorial team
  - o Lead development of an editorial CMS to allow for management of static content within the site
- > Interviewing/surveying to gain feedback for future functionalities to add to the UX and functionality development for the core platform
- > Reporting to the CTO on newly completed features/bug fixing as well as planning future tasks for completion

#### GRAPHIC DESIGNER | SELF EMPLOYED | JANUARY 2009 - PRESENT

- > Research & image sourcing (sometimes using own photography) for given brief/theme
- > Creating rough drafts based on initial ideas (of my own & of the client)
  - o Flyers
  - Digital Album Artwork
  - o 12" Vinyl Sleeves/Labels
- > Modifying/revising the rough draft based on client feedback
- > Providing final deliverables for print

#### **Education**

## BSC - COMPUTER SCIENCE | SEPTEMBER 2011 - JUNE 2014 | BRUNEL UNIVERSITY

- > Completed a final year project which included analysis of codebases/modification of Eclipse plug-ins to educate first-year Computer Science students on best practices of coding, coding conventions & avoiding bad code smells
- > Participation in group projects which included:
  - Developing an Android app (using Java) which allowed citizens to report local issues in their council/borough
  - Creating a website (using HTML, CSS & JS) which educated first year Computer Science students about placement schemes

- > Creation of an educational card game (using the XNA framework C++) which helped students practice conversion of decimal to binary, hexadecimal & two's complement
- > Partial learning & understanding of Python, project management, usability & networking protocols

# 3 A\*-B A LEVELS (COMPUTING, BUSINESS STUDIES & PHOTOGRAPHY) 8 A-C GCSES (INCLUDING MATHS & ENGLISH)

#### **Technical Skills**

- · Strong knowledge of HTML5 (partial knowledge of BEM naming syntax for classes)
- · Strong knowledge of CSS3/SCSS
- · jQuery (and Javascript)
- Handlebars
- · Gulp
- · Git (and Gitflow)
- · Experience with PHP (using the Laravel framework)
- · Experience with SQL
- · Strong knowledge of Photoshop
- · Experience with Java & C++

## **Interests**

My main hobby is music production (specializing in Drum & Bass/Jungle). I've been producing for just over 6 years and have had songs released on various Drum & Bass record labels. I've also had some of my songs played in clubs worldwide (as well as playing DJ sets in clubs in the UK) & on radio stations like BBC 1Xtra, Kiss FM, Rinse FM & NTS Radio, by a variety of DJs/other producers.